BARIS TEMEL

Mobile Phone:+90(539) 747-7377 ♦ Address:Istanbul, Turkey

 $E-Mail:btemel@sabanciuniv.edu \diamond LinkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/baris-temel/ \diamond Portfolio:https://btemel.github.io/linkedin.com/in/baris-temel/ \diamond Portfolio:https://btemel.github.com/in/baris-temel/ \diamond Portfolio:https://btemel/ openless.github.com/in/baris-temel/ openless.github.com/$

SUMMARY

I hold an Industrial Engineering degree from Sabanci University and an M.Sc. in Data Science from Sabanci University. I have 5 years of experience in data analytics, visualization, business intelligence, and data science fields.

I am a pro at self-management and a quick learner. I am a cheerful and solution-oriented person with decent communication skills, and I have a genuine interest in hot data science topics. Hence, I enjoy what I'm doing.

SKILLS

Software Languages
Python, SQL, R, Matlab, C++
OpenAI, LangChain, Pinecone, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Spark, Numpy, Scikit, Matplotlib
Tools
Azure Cloud Services, MS Copilot, Power BI & Tableau, Git, Docker, Jira, MS Office
Prompt Engineering, Communication, Resilience, Public Speaking, Time Management

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist The Coca-Cola Company

02/2023 - Present Istanbul, Turkey

- Working on building Data Science & Advanced Analytics solutions for cross-functional teams.
- Using Microsoft Azure Platforms to utilize Data Science solutions.
- Building & Improving Gen AI Applications using multiple LLMs. Working on use cases such as harmonizing using vector search, recommendation engine, and integrating Plugins and Assistants to our work stream.
- Harmonizing multiple external data sources such as Macroeconomics, Weather, and COVID Mobility with our company data and creating meaningful Insights & ML Solutions.
- Working on Clustering & Key Driver Analysis solutions for top 40 countries.
- Improving Coca-Cola Data Governance processes on EME OU over 25 countries. Responsible for the improvement & validation tasks of Nielsen who is a leader in delivering marketing information.
- Constructed an in-house Revenue Time Series forecasting solution on BIP (Business Integrated Planner), making a first for the EME. By consolidating various data sources, we successfully completed data modeling and visualization for the MVP of the Benchmark Tool.

Data Scientist REEF

08/2021 - 05/2022 $Miami. \ US$

- Responsible for designing and implementing BI solutions mainly to Kitchen verticals for Strategy and Operational KPIs.
- Architect and build Tableau Dashboards to achieve stakeholder needs.
- Created data structures using REST APIs / SQL / Python.
- Developed Supply Chain Dashboards for Pareto Analysis& Inventory Management System.
- Developed Market Analysis by creating automated scrapers in Python using state of art libraries such as Beautiful Soup, and Selenium.
- Analyzed sentiment analysis on partner delivery service platforms for executives.
- Developed a dashboard for tracking the performance of new employees' training development.
- Developed and improved the back end of over 20 Kitchen Dashboards using Redshift.

Teaching Assistant Sabanci University 09/2020 - 06/2022 Istanbul, Turkey

- Taught as an assistant for the introductory Python programming course IF 100 Computational Approaches to Problem Solving.
- Managed to teach up to intermediate-level concepts on coding to freshman students in one term for about 14 weeks.

Data Analyst QNB Finansbank

03/2019 - 06/2020 Istanbul, Turkey

- Management trainee: Trained financial and leadership skills, Python, SQL, and Excel training, and finished a project about credit card fraud detection.
- Koc University MT-MBA Education Program: Learned about macroeconomics, data analytics, and visualizations in real-world problems. The lectures give an insight into the MBA program.
- Analyzed raw data about financial concepts, creating algorithms and models in both Python and R gathering and exporting data using SQL, automating reports, and creating a visual platform in Visual Studio using C# and SQL, experiencing in creating different dashboards and making financial data analysis.

EDUCATION

Masters of Science - MS, Data Science, Sabanci University

09/2020 - 12/2022

- Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Big Data Processing, Deep NLP, Computer Graphics, Methods of Statistical Inference, Engineering Optimization, Advanced Statistics with R
- GPA: 3.50/4.00

Bachelor of Industrial Engineering, Sabanci University

09/2014 - 12/2018

- Relevant Coursework: Statistical Modelling, Deterministic & Stochastic Models in Operational Research, Financial Engineering, Decision Analysis, Simulation, Differential Equations, Supply Chain Practice, Quality Planning & Control, Decision Economics, Microeconomics
- GPA: 3.01/4.00

PROJECTS

Follower Anomalies in Social Media: This is my thesis project. The motivation is to create an open-source algorithm that detects anomalies of followers in any social media. Twitter is my base target social media. I am analyzing social bot movements. You can read the full thesis from this url.(Sabanci University 22')

Statistical Inference Tools: Building a new Framework for ANOVA & Multiple Linear Regression: Creating necessary packages that do not exist in famous data analysis libraries in Python. (Sabanci University 22')

Sphere Guided 3D Shape Generation and Manipulation: Implementing SP-GAN to human dataset. Creating 3D meshes from point clouds. (Sabanci University 21')

Face image generation with variational autoencoder: This project aims to create a face generation model using multiple VAEs for CelebA, FER13, and Emotic datasets. With this project, we have investigated the VAE architecture over images and 3D meshes, where we have practiced PyTorch and PyTorch geometric to generate synthetic images and meshes with different network architectures and datasets. (Sabanci University 20')

Cryptocurrency Price Trend Prediction Learning using LSTM Networks: This project is for a Deep Learning graduate course. The purpose is to create an LSTM network that will try to predict the trend movements. The aim was to learn how to build an LSTM network with real-time streaming data. (Sabanci University 20')

Deep Reinforcement Learning Project in Simulating Natural Selection Environment: It is my Machine Learning graduate course project that simulates a Natural Selection environment that includes prey & predator agents that learn using DDPG algorithm in Reinforcement Learning. (Sabanci University 20')